<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Covenant of Disaster</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="diabolist-covenant-disaster.xml" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-NURlrWVNuug8T2AKFLa" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Covenant of Disaster" type="Archetype" source="Mythical Conquest" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_COVENANT_DISASTER">
		<supports>Covenant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Diabolists of the Covenant of Disaster embody the chaos and destruction of the natural world. Their power is felt in storms of all kinds, from tempests and tornadoes to cyclones and hurricanes. Wind and lightning assaults their foes, stopping at nothing to wreak havoc on a wide scale. You can never quite predict these diabolists, as chaos is in their very nature.</p>
			<div element="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_TEMPESTUOUS"/>
			<div element="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_STORM_SURGE"/>
			<div element="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_VIOLENT_SQUALL"/>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_TEMPESTUOUS" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_STORM_SURGE" level="7"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_VIOLENT_SQUALL" level="15"/>
		</rules>
	</element>		
	<element name="Tempestuous" type="Archetype Feature" source="Mythical Conquest" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_TEMPESTUOUS">
		<description>
			<p>When you gain this covenant at 2nd level, you become as chaotic and swift as the storm. You have resistance to lightning damagem, and your corruptions additional damage type becomes lightning. Additionally, your speed increases by 10 feet, and you can take the Disengage action as a bonus action, and at the start of each of your turns, you can choose a number of creatures within 10 feet of you equal to your Corruption stage. The chosen creatures cannot take reactions until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You can take the Disengage action as a bonus action, and at the start of each of your turns, you can choose a number of creatures within 10ft. of you equal to your Corruption stage. The chosen creatures cannot take reactions until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="diabolist-covenant:damage_type" value="Lightning" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
			<stat name="diabolist:tempestuous_movement" value="10" bonus="Tempestuous" />
			
		</rules>
	</element>		
	<element name="Storm Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Mythical Conquest" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_STORM_SURGE">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, you can move like lightning. As a Bonus Action at the start of your turn while you are corrupted, you can immediately fly a number of feet equal to 5 x your Constitution Modifier. If you move within 5ft. of a hostile creature during this movement, that creature must make a Dexterity saving throw against your diabolist spell save DC, taking lightning damage equal to your Diabolist Level + your Constitution modifier on a failed saving throw or half as much on a success. You can only use this feature twice per long rest, gaining an additional use at 10th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="diabolist:storm_surge_uses/Long Rest">
			<description>
				<p>At the start of your turn while Corrupted, you can immediately fly {{diabolist:storm_surge_flight}}ft. If you move within 5ft. of a hostile creature during this movement, that creature must make a DC {{diabolist:dc}} DEX Saving Throw, taking {{diabolist:storm_surge_damage}} Lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much on a success.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_flight" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_flight" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_flight" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_flight" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_flight" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_damage" value="constitution:modifier"/>
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_damage" value="diabolist:level"/>
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_uses" value="2" />
			<stat name="diabolist:storm_surge_uses" value="1" level="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Violent Squall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Mythical Conquest" id="ID_MYTHIC_ARCHETYPE_DIABOLIST_FEATURE_VIOLENT_SQUALL">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, you can assault your enemies with wind. As an action, you can choose any number of creatures within 30 feet of you. Each chosen creature must make a Strength saving throw against your diabolist spell save DC or either be pulled 30 feet towards you or pushed 30 feet away from you in a straight line (you decide which), and then knocked prone. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>
				<p>Choose any number of creatures within 30ft. of you. Each chosen creature must make a DC {{diabolist:dc}}Strength saving throw or either be pulled 30ft. towards you or pushed 30ft. away from you in a straight line (you decide which), and then knocked prone.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>